{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Women","incorrectAnswers":["Jane Eyre","The Sisters Karamazov","Showgirls"],"question":"What novel written by Louisa May Alcott follows the lives of girls called Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Kenya","Bangladesh","Niger"],"question":"Which of these countries is part of the Arab League?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Korea","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","China","Russia"],"question":"Which country developed Tae-Kwan-Do?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pirate","incorrectAnswers":["Judge","Prime Minister","General"],"question":" What was Sir Henry Morgan famous for in the 17th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kosovo","incorrectAnswers":["Afghanistan","Kiribati","Greece"],"question":"Pristina is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mexico City ","incorrectAnswers":["Washington D.C.","Ottawa","San José"],"question":"What's the oldest capital city in the Americas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Linkin Park","incorrectAnswers":["Alice in Chains","Hollywood Undead","System of a Down"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'A Thousand Suns'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A quip","incorrectAnswers":["A type of hat","A food dish","A dance move"],"question":"What is the meaning of the term 'bon mot'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lordi","incorrectAnswers":["Nightwish","Poets of the Fall","Stratovarius"],"question":"Which Finnish hard rock band released the studio album 'To Beast or Not to Beast'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cougette","incorrectAnswers":["Aubergine","Avocado","Sweet Potato"],"question":"What Vegetable Is Also Known As Zuchinni?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"8","incorrectAnswers":["4","12","16"],"question":"In volume measurements, how many fluid ounces are there in a cup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Anthony Hopkins","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Hanks","Ewan McGregor","Arnold Schwarzenegger"],"question":"Which actor has starred in Thor and Westworld?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Austroasiatic","Uralic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Chhattisgarhi' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pablo Picasso","incorrectAnswers":["‎Salvador Dalí","Vincent van Gogh","Pierre-Auguste Renoir"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Portrait of Dora Maar\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert De Niro","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Duvall","John Hurt","Jack Lemmon"],"question":"Who won the 1980 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Jake LaMotta in Raging Bull?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Northern Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Art Nouveau","Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","Primitivism"],"question":"The painting \"The Arnolfini Marriage\" by Jan van Eyck is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jim Jones","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Matthews","Tom Taylor","Brian Bosworth"],"question":"Which cult leader led 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1979?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"32","incorrectAnswers":["22","42","52"],"question":"How old was Alexander the Great when he died ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1961","incorrectAnswers":["1947","1954","1968"],"question":"In which year was the first human sent into space?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Octothorpe","incorrectAnswers":["Firman","Xertz","Lackadaisical"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'the symbol #'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Samoa ","incorrectAnswers":["Tonga","Vanuatu","Tuvalu"],"question":"Which Pacific Nation Gained Independence From New Zealand In 1962?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sariputra","incorrectAnswers":["Aristotle","Mahavira","Confucius"],"question":"Who was an early pupil of Buddha in the 6th century B.C.?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tropic of Capricorn","incorrectAnswers":["Tropic of Cancer","Tropic of Libra","Tropic of Virgo"],"question":"Which tropic passes through Australia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"R. Kelly","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Drake","Ludacris"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'I Believe I Can Fly'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Buck","incorrectAnswers":["A Ram","A Billy","A Boar"],"question":"What is a male hamster known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"John Wayne","incorrectAnswers":["Burt Lancaster","Mel Gibson","Jack Nicholson"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Ethan Edwards in The Searchers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Luanda","incorrectAnswers":["Chisinau","Ngerulmud","Tbilisi"],"question":"What is the capital city of Angola?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belize","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Honduras","El Salvador"],"question":"Which Central American country extends furthest North?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pig","incorrectAnswers":["Rabbit","Cow","Horse"],"question":"What animal's meat can a Muslim not eat?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iceland","incorrectAnswers":["France","Uruguay","Luxembourg"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Blue with a red cross outlined in white extending to the edges.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Puerto Rico","incorrectAnswers":["Sweden","Sri Lanka","Iceland"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Five equal horizontal bands of red alternating with white. A blue triangle on the left containing a white star.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","Thailand","India"],"question":"In which country would you find the terracotta warriors?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Who","incorrectAnswers":["What","When","Where"],"question":"In French, what does the word 'qui' translate to?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Puttin' on the Ritz","incorrectAnswers":["Barbie Girl","Turn the Beat Around","What I Am"],"question":"Taco had a one hit wonder in 1983 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John Adams","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Jefferson","Andrew Jackson","James Monroe"],"question":"Who was George Washington's vice-president?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vatican City","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra","San Marino","Monaco"],"question":"What is the smallest independent state in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["The Netherlands","France","Scotland"],"question":"In what country is the Waterloo battlefield?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Suum cuique","incorrectAnswers":["Fons vitae caritas","In absentia lucis, tenebrae vincunt","Melita, domi adsum"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases translates to 'To each his own'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Styx","incorrectAnswers":["Hela","Doomwater","Xerxes"],"question":"In Greek Mythology, What is the name of the most famous of the rivers in the Underworld??","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Ernest Wiseman","incorrectAnswers":["Jeffrey Wallis","Lars Friedel","Matthew Flaunt"],"question":"What was the real name of Eric Morecambes partner?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Kit","incorrectAnswers":["A Hatchling","A Larva","An Owlet"],"question":"A young squirrel is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kuala Lumpur","incorrectAnswers":["Singapore","Seoul","Tokyo"],"question":"The Petronas Towers are a pair of iconic skyscrapers located in what city?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Richard Nixon","incorrectAnswers":["John F Kennedy","Abraham Lincoln","Ronald Reagan"],"question":"Which US President was forced to resign in 1974?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Glen Campbell","incorrectAnswers":["Johnny Cash","Willie Nelson","Kenny Rogers"],"question":"Which country star had hits including \"Rhinestone Cowboy\" and \"Wichita Lineman\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["United States of America","Cuba","Ireland"],"question":"In what country is Thunder Bay?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["White","Rosé","Sparkling"],"question":"What type of wine is Beaujolais Nouveau?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Orzo","incorrectAnswers":["Pastina","Strozzapreti","Bavette"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Barley'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"3M","incorrectAnswers":["Sun Microsystems","Teflon","Del Monte"],"question":"Which parent company is known for manufacturing Post-it notes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"October 31st","incorrectAnswers":["November 10th","October 24th","November 21st"],"question":"On Which Date Is Halloween?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jeremy Bentham","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Epictetus","René Descartes"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The greatest happiness of the greatest number is the foundation of morals and legislation'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Snap! Crackle! Pop!","incorrectAnswers":["Eat Mor Chikin","A glass and a half in every half pound","Melts in your mouth, not in your hands."],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Rice Krispies?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bird","incorrectAnswers":["Kangaroo","Lion","Elephant"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Twitter logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thimphu","incorrectAnswers":["Mogadishu","Montevideo","Bamako"],"question":"What is the capital city of Bhutan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Elizabeth Banks","incorrectAnswers":["Sandra Bæ Hovedr","Penélope Cruz","Emma Thompson"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in films including Spider-Man and The Hunger Games?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bing Crosby","incorrectAnswers":["John Lennon","Aretha Franklin","Madonna"],"question":"Who did David Bowie duet with on the Christmas Hit 'Little Drummer Boy''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Sow","incorrectAnswers":["A Nanny","A Lioness","A Vixen"],"question":"What would you call a female skunk?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Federated States of Micronesia is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Black","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Argentina?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A field","incorrectAnswers":["A parliament","A yoke","A troop"],"question":"What is the word for a group of racehorses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is commonly used as a condiment and food preservative.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used to relieve pain.","It is used in thermometers, thermostats, barometers","It is used in nuclear reactors, as a neutron moderator."],"question":"What is the chemical sodium chloride often used for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Smirnoff","incorrectAnswers":["Japan Airlines","Peugeot","Hermès"],"question":"Which of these brands has a eagle on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Risk","incorrectAnswers":["Monopoly","Trivial Pursuit","Life"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must conquer the world by building armies and invading other players' territories?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Black Sea","incorrectAnswers":["The Baltic Sea","The Mediterranean Sea","The Caspian Sea"],"question":"What is the name of the sea that is bordered by Romania to the west, Ukraine to the north, Russia to the east, and Turkey to the south?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brisbane","incorrectAnswers":["Queenstown","Auckland","Christchurch"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Australia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bang bang","incorrectAnswers":["Yeah yeah","Hey hey","Go go"],"question":"What two-word musical exclamation is used by The Beatles before \"Maxwell's Silver Hammer\" comes down on various heads?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Austronesian","incorrectAnswers":["Indo-European","Niger–Congo","Kra–Dai"],"question":"The language 'Tagalog' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Judy Garland","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Bancroft","Olivia Newton-John","Vivien Leigh"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Dorothy Gale in The Wizard of Oz?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I’m just one stomach flu away from my goal weight.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I'll be back.\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\"","\"I'm the king of the world!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Devil Wears Prada'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"friction at very small scale","incorrectAnswers":["wood","ticks and mites","the Earth"],"question":"What is Nanotribology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bertrand Russell","incorrectAnswers":["Denis Diderot","Jean-Paul Sartre","Jean-Jacques Rousseau"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'I would never die for my beliefs because I might be wrong'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Elvis Presley","Prince","David Bowie"],"question":"Which pop star is known as 'The King of Pop'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baltimore Ravens","incorrectAnswers":["Baltimore Blues","Baltimore Crew","Baltimore Wizards"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Baltimore?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rome","incorrectAnswers":["Milan","Naples","Florence"],"question":"In which city is the colosseum located?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Puebla","incorrectAnswers":["San Juan","Curitiba","Nassau"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Mexico?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Shari'a","incorrectAnswers":["Halakha","Karma","Dharma"],"question":"What is the name of the Islamic law?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Korea","Laos"],"question":"Which country was divided into North And South in 1954 after the French colonial government was forced out?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Erik The Red ","incorrectAnswers":["Ragnar Lothbrok","Leif Erikson","Canute"],"question":"Which Viking Chief Founded The Norse Colonies On Greenland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Alice in Chains","incorrectAnswers":["Poison","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American grunge band released the studio album 'Black Gives Way to Blue'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Motor racing","incorrectAnswers":["Basketball","Baseball","Swimming"],"question":"With which sport is Lewis Hamilton associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bazooka","incorrectAnswers":["Grenade","Mortar","HIMARS"],"question":"What is the name of the shoulder-held weapon used for firing armor-piercing rockets?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Salma Hayek","incorrectAnswers":["Frances Fisher","Rachel Weisz","Keira Knightley"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in films including Traffic and Eternals?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cheyenne, Wyoming","incorrectAnswers":["Santa Fe, New Mexico","Helena, Montana","Pierre, South Dakota"],"question":"What is the name of the state capital located about 100 miles north of Denver?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Jim Thorpe","incorrectAnswers":["Jesse Owens","Carl Lewis","Muhammad Ali"],"question":"Which American athlete won both the pentathlon and decathlon in the 1912 Summer Olympics in Stockholm?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mount Pelée","incorrectAnswers":["Krakatoa","Mount St Helen's","Mount Pinatubo"],"question":"Which volcano erupted in 1902, killing 30,000?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chemist and founder of microbiology.","incorrectAnswers":["Italian explorer who landed in America.","Inventor of the printing press.","An influential figure in Sunni Islam."],"question":"Which of the following describes Antony van Leeuwenhoek?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band (1970-) released the song 'Crazy Little Thing Called Love'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tanzania","incorrectAnswers":["Cuba","Iran","Nigeria"],"question":"In which country would you find the Serengeti National Park?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Scattering","incorrectAnswers":["Cohesion","Adhesion","Diffusion"],"question":"In physics, what phenomenon can be defined as \"a change in the direction of motion of a particle because of a collision with another particle\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Skiing","Rugby Union","Gymnastics"],"question":"With which sport is Paula Radcliffe associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bonsai","incorrectAnswers":["Ornamental Shrubbery","Decorage","Topiary"],"question":"What is the name given to the art of miniaturising trees and maintaining their small size?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Southeast Asia","incorrectAnswers":["China","South America","Central Asia"],"question":"From which part of the world do oranges originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Nymph","incorrectAnswers":["A Kitten","A Hatchling","A Chick"],"question":"A young cockroach is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ulysses","incorrectAnswers":["We Have Always Lived in the Castle","The Quiet American","The Sound and the Fury"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Leopold Bloom'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vladivostok","incorrectAnswers":["Moscow","Saint Petersburg","Nizhny Novgorod"],"question":"Which of these Russian cities is not located in European Russia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Jackson 5","incorrectAnswers":["The Osmonds","The Temptations","The Supremes"],"question":"Which family group had four No. 1 hits in 1970, including 'ABC'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roy Scheider","incorrectAnswers":["Harrison Ford","Robert De Niro","Jack Nicholson"],"question":"Which actor made his debut in the lesser-known film \"The Curse of the Living Corpse\" before achieving fame with \"Jaws\" and \"All that Jazz\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Skeleton Crew'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Johannes Kepler","incorrectAnswers":["Nicolaus Copernicus","Tycho Brahe","Galileo Galilei"],"question":"Who was the German astronomer who discovered in the early 17th century that the planets orbit the sun in ellipses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["The Lord of the Rings","A Song of Ice and Fire","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Albus Dumbledore' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},